Nikhil Sharma

Android Developer

Phone: 8123352756

Address: Bengaluru, India

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/p

ub/nikhil-

sharma/4a/108/938

Email: nikhil.sharma.it@gmail.com

I am Android application developer, with working experience of **2.6 years** both in native and hybrid applications of mobile, I am working with clients like Lakme, Tony & Guy, HUL, GSK, TataSky and many more. I am working with Peel-works as a lead for android team, and in my earlier experience I got client service awards for clients like McDonalds and FourthLion. A good team player, energetic, clean coder and good listener. I am a B.Tech from Rajasthan Technical University.

Experience

Peel-works

Senior Software Developer

Worked in projects like 9-yards, Lakme, Airtel, Tata Sky

Neev Information Technologies

Software Developer

Worked in projects like McD Germany, TonyAndGuy, FourthLion, Dishgram

C-DAC (Formerly NCST)

trainee

Software Development, Web development

AUGUST 2011 TO AUGUST

AUGUST 2012 TO MAY 2014

JUNE 2014 TO PRESENT

2012

2003 TO 2004

2005 TO 2006

2007 TO 2011

Education

RBSE

Seconday

70%

RBSE

Sr. Secondary

60%

Rajasthan technical university

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)

63%

Android, Java, MySQL, Sqlite, AngularJS, PhoneGap, InetlliJ

Skills

https://9yards.peelworks.com/peelworkscustomer/

9-Yards is a product of peelworks. And this is for HR management. And we are having great clients like HUL, GSK, Tatasky, Airtel, Pepsi, any many more.

In this we are managing all the incentive, their attendance, promotions, pay-rolls etc.

My role is to create the mobile interface to that product. so all the employee can check their progress. It include all the feature which are available in the web.

Technologies used: Android SDK.

Libraries: Picaso, GreenDAO, Crashlytics, and many more

Lakme

JUN 2014 TO OCT 2014

Lakme is a counter management application, to manage the stylist at the counter, their attendance and the stock update, sales, complaint management, and skill development. My responsibilities was to develop the UI, backend integration with web Rest api, database management, Image processing.

Technologies used: Android SDK, Groovy on Grails for server side, SQLite for database management.

Libraries used: Picaso, Crashlytics, android supportV4, etc

McDonalds Germany

FEB 2014 TO MAY 2014

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.mcdonalds.mcdonaldsinfoapp&hl=en

McD is a famous fast food chain, and we got the chance to McD app maintenance, It was a promotion feature for McD at the time of FIFA world cup 2014. User have to collect the coupons from the McD boxes and send via app and they get the gifts according to it. My responsibilities was to develop the UI, backend integration with Rest api, And integrating ABBYY library.

Technologies used: Android SDK **Libraries used**: Picaso, ABBYY, etc

FourthLion

OCT 2013 TO FEB 2014

It a phonegap based application for campaigning management. Organize and schedule meetings, Invites and promotions

My responsibilities was to develop the UI, backend integration with web Rest api, database management, Image processing.

Technologies used: Phonegap, cordova, angularJs, Groovy on Grails for server side, SQLite for database management.

Libraries used: Picaso, Crashlytics, android supportV4, etc

Tony & Guy

AUG 2013 TO OCT 2013

http://toniandguy.com/

Tony & Guy is a counter management application, to manage the stylist at the counter, their attendance and the stock update, sales, complaint management, and skill

development.

My responsibilities was to develop the UI, backend integration with web Rest api, database management, Image processing.

Technologies used: Android SDK, Groovy on Grails for server side, SQLite for database management.

Libraries used: Picaso, Crashlytics, android supportV4, etc

Dishgram

JAN 2013 TO JULY 2013

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dishgram.android&hl=en

Dishgram is a app where you can find the best restaurants and food nearby. My responsibilities was to develop the UI, backend integration with web Rest api, Image processing.

Technologies used: Android SDK, Groovy on Grails for server side, SQLite for database management.

Libraries used: Picaso, Crashlytics, android supportV4, etc